<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T20:09:29Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0704.0712" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0704.0712</identifier>
 <datestamp>2009-11-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Interference effects in above-threshold ionization from diatomic
  molecules: determining the internuclear separation</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Hetzheim, H.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Faria, C. Figueira de Morisson</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Becker, W.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Atomic Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We calculate angle-resolved above-threshold ionization spectra for diatomic
molecules in linearly polarized laser fields, employing the strong-field
approximation. The interference structure resulting from the individual
contributions of the different scattering scenarios is discussed in detail,
with respect to the dependence on the internuclear distance and molecular
orientation. We show that, in general, the contributions from the processes in
which the electron is freed at one center and rescatters off the other obscure
the interference maxima and minima obtained from single-center processes.
However, around the boundary of the energy regions for which rescattering has a
classical counterpart, such processes play a negligible role and very clear
interference patterns are observed. In such energy regions, one is able to
infer the internuclear distance from the energy difference between adjacent
interference minima.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 10 pages, 8 figures; discussions slightly modified and an additional
  figure inserted for clarity</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2007-04-05</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2007-06-15</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0704.0712</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevA.76.023418</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
