<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-08T15:40:13Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0704.0766" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0704.0766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-06-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Local de Broglie-Bohm Trajectories from Entangled Wavefunctions</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Clover, Michael</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We present a local interpretation of what is usually considered to be a
nonlocal de Broglie-Bohm trajectory prescription for an entangled singlet state
of massive particles. After reviewing various meanings of the term
``nonlocal'', we show that by using appropriately retarded wavefunctions (i.e.,
the locality loophole) this local model can violate Bell's inequality, without
making any appeal to detector inefficiencies.
  We analyze a possible experimental configuration appropriate to massive
two-particle singlet wavefunctions and find that as long as the particles are
not ultra-relativistic, a locality loophole exists and Dirac wave(s) can
propagate from Alice or Bob's changing magnetic field, through space, to the
other detector, arriving before the particle and thereby allowing a local
interpretation to the 2-particle de Broglie-Bohm trajectories.
  We also propose a physical effect due to changing magnetic fields in a
Stern-Gerlach EPR setup that will throw away events and create a detector
loophole in otherwise perfectly efficient detectors, an effect that is only
significant for near-luminal particles that might otherwise close the locality
loophole.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 11 pages, no figures v2: fix minor grammatical infelicities, added
  some references</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2007-04-05</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2007-06-27</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0704.0766</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
