<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-08T23:52:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1301.5345" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.5345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2014-04-07</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Quantum dynamics and kinematics from a statistical model selected by the
  principle of Locality</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Budiyono, Agung</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  Quantum mechanics predicts correlation between spacelike separated events
which is widely argued to violate the principle of Local Causality. By
contrast, here we shall show that the Schr\&quot;odinger equation with Born's
statistical interpretation of wave function and uncertainty relation can be
derived from a statistical model of microscopic stochastic deviation from
classical mechanics which is selected uniquely, up to a free parameter, by the
principle of Local Causality. Quantization is thus argued to be physical and
Planck constant acquires an interpretation as the average stochastic deviation
from classical mechanics in a microscopic time scale. Unlike canonical
quantization, the resulting quantum system always has a definite configuration
all the time as in classical mechanics, fluctuating randomly along a continuous
trajectory. The average of the relevant physical quantities over the
distribution of the configuration are shown to be equal numerically to the
quantum mechanical average of the corresponding Hermitian operators over a
quantum state.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 33 pages, no figure, major changes, accepted for publication in
  International Journal of Theoretical Physics</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2013-01-20</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2013-11-15</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.5345</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Int. J. Theor. Phys. 53, 1276 (2014)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1007/s10773-013-1925-4</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
