<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-08T16:22:53Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1505.00907" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-08-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Potential capacities of quantum channels</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Winter, Andreas</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Yang, Dong</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We introduce the notion of potential capacities of quantum channels in an
operational way and provide upper bounds for these quantities, which quantify
the ultimate limit of usefulness of a channel for a given task in the best
possible context.
  Unfortunately, except for a few isolated cases, potential capacities seem to
be as hard to compute as their &quot;plain&quot; analogues. We thus study upper bounds on
some potential capacities: For the classical capacity, we give an upper bound
in terms of the entanglement of formation. To establish a bound for the quantum
and private capacity, we first &quot;lift&quot; the channel to a Hadamard channel and
then prove that the quantum and private capacity of Hadamard channel is
strongly additive, implying that for these channels, potential and plain
capacity are equal. Employing these upper bounds we show that if a channel is
noisy, however close it is to the noiseless channel, then it cannot be
activated into the noiseless channel by any other contextual channel; this
conclusion holds for all the three capacities.
  Although it is of less importance, we also discuss the so-called
environment-assisted quantum capacity, because we are able to characterize its
&quot;potential&quot; version.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 15 pages; in v2 minor changes, typos fixed and new references added;
  in v3 extended reference to &quot;quantum value added&quot; precedent of potential
  capacities; v4 has new results on fair pricing of quantum channels wrt to
  quantum and private communication</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2015-08-14</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1505.00907</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
