<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-02-28T15:07:14Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1712.00610" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.00610</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>General Solution of the Schr\&quot;odinger Equation with Potential Field
  Quantization</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Erbil, Hasan H&#xfc;seyin</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  It has been found a simple procedure for the general solution of the
time-independent Schr\&quot;odinger equation (SE) with the help of quantization of
potential area in one dimension without making any approximation. Energy values
are not dependent on wave functions, so to find the energy values; it is enough
to find the classic turning points of the potential function. Two different
solutions were obtained, namely, symmetric and antisymmetric at bound states.
These normalized wave functions are always periodic. It is enough to take the
integral of the square root of the potential energy function to find the
normalized wave functions. If these calculations cannot be made analytically,
it should then be performed by numerical methods. SE has been solved for a
particle in many one-dimension and the spherical symmetric central potential
well as examples. It has been found their energies and normalized wave
functions as examples. These solutions were also applied to the theories of
scattering and alpha decay. The results obtained with the experimental values
were compared with the calculated values. One has been seen to be very fit.
</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2017-12-02</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1712.00610</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
