<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-02-28T15:07:11Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1712.00502" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.00502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Analysing correlated noise on the surface code using adaptive decoding
  algorithms</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Nickerson, Naomi H.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Brown, Benjamin J.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  Laboratory hardware is rapidly progressing towards a state where quantum
error-correcting codes can be realised. As such, we must learn how to deal with
the complex nature of the noise that may occur in real physical systems. Single
qubit Pauli errors are commonly used to study the behaviour of error-correcting
codes, but in general we might expect the environment to introduce correlated
errors to a system. Given some knowledge of structures that errors commonly
take, it may be possible to adapt the error-correction procedure to compensate
for this noise, but performing full state tomography on a physical system to
analyse this structure quickly becomes impossible as the size increases beyond
a few qubits. Here we develop and test new methods to analyse correlated errors
by making use of a parametrised families of decoding algorithms. We demonstrate
our method numerically using a diffusive noise model. We show that information
can be learnt about the parameters of the noise model, and additionally that
the logical error rates can be improved. We conclude by discussing how our
method could be utilised in a practical setting.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 11 pages, 8 figures, comments welcome; v2 - minor typos corrected
  some references added</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2017-12-11</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1712.00502</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
