<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T18:52:47Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0410015" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0410015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2009-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Bell's theorem: Critique of proofs with and without inequalities</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Hess, Karl</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Philipp, Walter</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  Most of the standard proofs of the Bell theorem are based on the Kolmogorov
axioms of probability theory. We show that these proofs contain mathematical
steps that cannot be reconciled with the Kolmogorov axioms. Specifically we
demonstrate that these proofs ignore the conclusion of a theorem of Vorob'ev on
the consistency of joint distributions. As a consequence Bell's theorem stated
in its full generality remains unproven, in particular, for extended parameter
spaces that are still objective local and that include instrument parameters
that are correlated by both time and instrument settings. Although the Bell
theorem correctly rules out certain small classes of hidden variables, for
these extended parameter spaces the standard proofs come to a halt. The
Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) approach is based on similar fallacious
arguments. For this case we are able to present an objective local computer
experiment that simulates the experimental test of GHZ performed by Pan,
Bouwmeester, Daniell, Weinfurter and Zeilinger and that directly contradicts
their claim that Einstein-local elements of reality can neither explain the
results of quantum mechanical theory nor their experimental results.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 13 pages</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2004-10-01</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0410015</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1063/1.1874568</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
