<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T19:03:40Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0409214" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0409214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2009-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Quantum phase-space analysis of the pendular cavity</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Olsen, M. K.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Melo, A. B.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Dechoum, K.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Khoury, A. Z.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We perform a quantum mechanical analysis of the pendular cavity, using the
positive-P representation, showing that the quantum state of the moving mirror,
a macroscopic object, has noticeable effects on the dynamics. This system has
previously been proposed as a candidate for the quantum-limited measurement of
small displacements of the mirror due to radiation pressure, for the production
of states with entanglement between the mirror and the field, and even for
superposition states of the mirror. However, when we treat the oscillating
mirror quantum mechanically, we find that it always oscillates, has no
stationary steady-state, and exhibits uncertainties in position and momentum
which are typically larger than the mean values. This means that previous
linearised fluctuation analyses which have been used to predict these highly
quantum states are of limited use. We find that the achievable accuracy in
measurement is far worse than the standard quantum limit due to thermal noise,
which, for typical experimental parameters, is overwhelming even at 2 mK.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 25 pages, 6 figures To be published in Phys. Rev. A</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2004-09-30</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0409214</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevA.70.043815</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
