<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T19:26:19Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0204038" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0204038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Trading quantum for classical resources in quantum data compression</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Hayden, Patrick</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Jozsa, Richard</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Winter, Andreas</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We study the visible compression of a source E of pure quantum signal states,
or, more formally, the minimal resources per signal required to represent
arbitrarily long strings of signals with arbitrarily high fidelity, when the
compressor is given the identity of the input state sequence as classical
information. According to the quantum source coding theorem, the optimal
quantum rate is the von Neumann entropy S(E) qubits per signal.
  We develop a refinement of this theorem in order to analyze the situation in
which the states are coded into classical and quantum bits that are quantified
separately. This leads to a trade--off curve Q(R), where Q(R) qubits per signal
is the optimal quantum rate for a given classical rate of R bits per signal.
  Our main result is an explicit characterization of this trade--off function
by a simple formula in terms of only single signal, perfect fidelity encodings
of the source. We give a thorough discussion of many further mathematical
properties of our formula, including an analysis of its behavior for group
covariant sources and a generalization to sources with continuously
parameterized states. We also show that our result leads to a number of
corollaries characterizing the trade--off between information gain and state
disturbance for quantum sources. In addition, we indicate how our techniques
also provide a solution to the so--called remote state preparation problem.
Finally, we develop a probability--free version of our main result which may be
interpreted as an answer to the question: ``How many classical bits does a
qubit cost?'' This theorem provides a type of dual to Holevo's theorem, insofar
as the latter characterizes the cost of coding classical bits into qubits.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 51 pages, 7 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2002-04-07</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0204038</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>J. Math. Phys. Vol. 43 No. 9 pp. 4404-4444 (2002)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1063/1.1497184</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
