<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T18:51:08Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0611281" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0611281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-06-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Decoherence Control in Open Quantum System via Classical Feedback</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Ganesan, Narayan</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Tarn, Tzyh Jong</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  In this work we propose a novel strategy using techniques from systems theory
to completely eliminate decoherence and also provide conditions under which it
can be done so. A novel construction employing an auxiliary system, the bait,
which is instrumental to decoupling the system from the environment is
presented. Our approach to decoherence control in contrast to other approaches
in the literature involves the bilinear input affine model of quantum control
system which lends itself to various techniques from classical control theory,
but with non-trivial modifications to the quantum regime. The elegance of this
approach yields interesting results on open loop decouplability and Decoherence
Free Subspaces(DFS). Additionally, the feedback control of decoherence may be
related to disturbance decoupling for classical input affine systems, which
entails careful application of the methods by avoiding all the quantum
mechanical pitfalls. In the process of calculating a suitable feedback the
system has to be restructured due to its tensorial nature of interaction with
the environment, which is unique to quantum systems. The results are
qualitatively different and superior to the ones obtained via master equations.
Finally, a methodology to synthesize feedback parameters itself is given, that
technology permitting, could be implemented for practical 2-qubit systems to
perform decoherence free Quantum Computing.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 17 pages, 4 Figs</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2006-11-29</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0611281</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevA.75.032323</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
