<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T19:26:12Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0204033" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0204033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>The Cosmic Digital Code and Quantum Mechanics</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Chung, Ding-Yu</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  This paper posits that the cosmic digital code as the law of all physical
laws contains two mutually exclusive values: attachment space attaching to
object and detachment space detaching from object. However, the cosmic physical
system could not start with mutually exclusive attachment space and detachment
space at the same time in the beginning. The way out of this impasse is that
the complete cosmic system consists of both the cosmic physical system and the
unphysical cosmic digital code. The unphysical cosmic digital code allows the
coexistence of attachment space and detachment space at the same time. The
cosmic digital code behaves as gene in organism, and the cosmic physical system
behaves as organ. Under different conditions and times, different spaces in the
cosmic digital code are activated to generate different spaces in the cosmic
physical systems with different physical laws for different universes in the
multivese. All universes start from the primitive multiverse, which only has
attachment space attaching to 10D string without the four force fields. During
the big bang in our universe, detachment space emerged to detach particle from
its four force fields. Such detachment, however, cannot be completely and
permanently detached, because particle still attaches to its force fields. The
result is hybrid space, combining both attachment space and detachment space in
coherent state, such as particle and its force fields. Hybrid space is the
space for wavefunction whose probability density is proportional to attachment
space, and inversely proportional to detachment space. The collapse of
wavefunction in decoherent state is the separation of attachment space and
detachment space in such way that attachment space attaches to particle, and
detachment space separately detaches from all probability density.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 7 pages</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2002-04-06</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2005-04-25</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0204033</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
