<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-08T15:40:58Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0704.1368" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0704.1368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Anisotropy and Magnetic Field Effects on the Genuine Multipartite
  Entanglement of Multi-Qubit Heisenberg {\it XY} Chains</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Kwong, Chang Chi</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Yeo, Ye</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  It has been shown that, for the two-qubit Heisenberg XY model, anisotropy and
magnetic field may together be used to produce entanglement for any finite
temperature by adjusting the external magnetic field beyond some finite
critical strength. This interesting result arises from an analysis employing
the Wootters concurrence, a computable measure of entanglement for two-qubit
states. Recently, Mintert {\em et al.} proposed generalizations of Wootters
concurrence for multipartite states. These MKB concurrences possess a
mathematical property that enables one to understand the origin of this
characteristic behavior. Here, we first study the effect of anisotropy and
magnetic field on the multipartite thermal entanglement of a four-qubit
Heisenberg XY chain using the MKB concurrences. We show that this model
exhibits characteristic behavior similar to that of the two-qubit model. In
addition, we show that this can again be understood using the same mathematical
property. Next, we show that the six-qubit Heisenberg XY chain possesses
properties necessary for it to have the characteristic behavior too. Most
importantly, it is possible to directly measure the multipartite MKB
concurrences of pure states. This may provide an experimental verification of
our conjecture that for a Heisenberg XY chain of any even number of qubits, it
is always possible to obtain non-zero genuine multipartite entanglement at any
finite temperature by applying a sufficiently large magnetic field.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 21 pages, 4 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2007-04-11</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2007-05-03</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0704.1368</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
