<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T19:14:00Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0704.0088" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0704.0088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Some new experimental photonic flame effect features</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Tcherniega, N. V.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  The results of the spectral, energetical and temporal characteristics of
radiation in the presence of the photonic flame effect are presented.
Artificial opal posed on Cu plate at the temperature of liquid nitrogen boiling
point (77 K) being irradiated by nanosecond ruby laser pulse produces long-
term luminiscence with a duration till ten seconds with a finely structured
spectrum in the the antistocks part of the spectrum. Analogous visible
luminescence manifesting time delay appeared in other samples of the artificial
opals posed on the same plate. In the case of the opal infiltrated with
different nonlinear liquids the threshold of the luminiscence is reduced and
the spatial disribution of the bright emmiting area on the opal surface is
being changed. In the case of the putting the frozen nonlinear liquids on the
Cu plate long-term blue bright luminiscence took place in the frozen species of
the liquids. Temporal characteristics of this luminiscence are nearly the same
as in opal matrixes.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 9 pages, 10 figures, accepted for publication in JRLR</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2007-04-01</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0704.0088</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
