<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T19:15:11Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0704.1742" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0704.1742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2009-11-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>nlin</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Surface gap solitons at a nonlinearity interface</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Dohnal, Tomas</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Pelinovsky, Dmitry</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Nonlinear Sciences - Pattern Formation and Solitons</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We demonstrate existence of waves localized at the interface of two nonlinear
periodic media with different coefficients of the cubic nonlinearity via the
one-dimensional Gross--Pitaevsky equation. We call these waves the surface gap
solitons (SGS). In the case of smooth symmetric periodic potentials, we study
analytically bifurcations of SGS's from standard gap solitons and determine
numerically the maximal jump of the nonlinearity coefficient allowing for the
SGS existence. We show that the maximal jump vanishes near the thresholds of
bifurcations of gap solitons. In the case of continuous potentials with a jump
in the first derivative at the interface, we develop a homotopy method of
continuation of SGS families from the solution obtained via gluing of parts of
the standard gap solitons and study existence of SGS's in the photonic band
gaps. We explain the termination of the SGS families in the interior points of
the band gaps from the bifurcation of linear bound states in the continuous
non-smooth potentials.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 23 pages, 6 figures, 3 tables corrections in v.2: sign error in the
  energy functional on p.3; discussion of the symmetries of Bloch functions on
  p. 5-6 corrected; derivative symbol missing in (3.5) and in the formula for
  \mu below (3.6)</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2007-04-13</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2009-04-01</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0704.1742</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1137/060676751</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
