<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T19:14:14Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0704.0703" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0704.0703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2009-11-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Transient behavior of surface plasmon polaritons scattered at a
  subwavelength groove</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Leveque, Gaetan</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Martin, Olivier J. F.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Weiner, John</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We present a numerical study and analytical model of the optical near-field
diffracted in the vicinity of subwavelength grooves milled in silver surfaces.
The Green's tensor approach permits computation of the phase and amplitude
dependence of the diffracted wave as a function of the groove geometry. It is
shown that the field diffracted along the interface by the groove is equivalent
to replacing the groove by an oscillating dipolar line source. An analytic
expression is derived from the Green's function formalism, that reproduces well
the asymptotic surface plasmon polariton (SPP) wave as well as the transient
surface wave in the near-zone close to the groove. The agreement between this
model and the full simulation is very good, showing that the transient
&quot;near-zone&quot; regime does not depend on the precise shape of the groove. Finally,
it is shown that a composite diffractive evanescent wave model that includes
the asymptotic SPP can describe the wavelength evolution in this transient
near-zone. Such a semi-analytical model may be useful for the design and
optimization of more elaborate photonic circuits whose behavior in large part
will be controlled by surface waves.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 12 pages, 10 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2007-04-05</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0704.0703</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevB.76.155418</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
