<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T20:44:44Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:0907.1866" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0907.1866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-05-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:cond-mat</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Density profiles and density oscillations of an interacting
  three-component normal Fermi gas</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>De Silva, Theja N.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Condensed Matter - Quantum Gases</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We use a semiclassical approximation to investigate density variations and
dipole oscillations of an interacting three-component normal Fermi gas in a
harmonic trap. We consider both attractive and repulsive interactions between
different pairs of fermions and study the effect of population imbalance on
densities. We find that the density profiles significantly deviate from those
of non-interacting profiles and extremely sensitive to interactions and
population imbalance. Unlike for a two-component Fermi system, we find density
imbalance even for balanced populations. For some range of parameters, one
component completely repels from the trap center giving rise a donut shape
density profile. Further, we find that the in-phase dipole oscillation
frequency is consistent with Kohn's theorem and other two dipole mode
frequencies are strongly effected by the interactions and the number of atoms
in the harmonic trap.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: Total seven pages with five figures. Published version</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2009-07-10</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2010-01-21</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/0907.1866</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 43 (2010) 035301</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1088/0953-4075/43/3/035301</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
