<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T20:38:37Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1203.1236" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1203.1236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-06-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:cond-mat</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Strong-coupling solution of the bosonic dynamical mean-field theory</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Kauch, Anna</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Byczuk, Krzysztof</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Vollhardt, Dieter</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Condensed Matter - Quantum Gases</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We derive an approximate analytical solution of the self-consistency
equations of the bosonic dynamical mean-field theory (B-DMFT) in the
strong-coupling limit. The approach is based on a linked-cluster expansion in
the hybridization function of normal bosons around the atomic limit. The
solution is used to compute the phase diagram of the bosonic Hubbard model for
different lattices. We compare our results with numerical solutions of the
B-DMFT equations and numerically exact methods, respectively. The very good
agreement with those numerical results demonstrates that our approach captures
the essential physics of correlated bosons both in the Mott insulator and in
the superfluid phase. Close to the transition into the superfluid phase the
momentum distribution function at zero momentum is found to be strongly
enhanced already in the normal phase. The linked-cluster expansion also allows
us to compute dynamical properties such as the spectral function of bosons. The
evolution of the spectral function across the transition from the normal to the
superfluid phase is seen to be characteristically different for the interaction
driven and density driven transition, respectively.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 8 pages, 6 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2012-03-06</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1203.1236</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Phys. Rev. B 85, 205115 (2012)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevB.85.205115</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
