<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T18:14:04Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1301.5366" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.5366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2013-01-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Electromagnetic Wave Source Conditions</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Oskooi, Ardavan</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Johnson, Steven G.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Computational Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  This chapter discusses the relationships between current sources and the
resulting electromagnetic waves in FDTD simulations. First, the
&quot;total-field/scattered-field&quot; approach to creating incident plane waves is
reviewed and seen to be a special case of the well-known principle of
equivalence in electromagnetism: this can be used to construct &quot;equivalent&quot;
current sources for any desired incident field, including waveguide modes. The
effects of dispersion and discretization are discussed, and a simple technique
to separate incident and scattered fields is described in order to compensate
for imperfect equivalent currents. The important concept of the local density
of states (LDOS) is reviewed, which elucidates the relationship between current
sources and the resulting fields, including enhancement of the LDOS via mode
cutoffs (Van Hove singularities) and resonant cavities (Purcell enhancement).
We also address various other source techniques such as covering a wide range
of frequencies and incident angles in a small number of simulations for waves
incident on a periodic surface, sources to excite eigenmodes in rectangular
supercells of periodic systems, moving sources, and thermal sources via a Monte
Carlo/Langevin approach.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: Excerpted from &quot;Advances in FDTD Computational Electrodynamics:
  Photonics and Nanotechnology,&quot; A. Taflove, A. Oskooi, and S.G. Johnson, eds.,
  Norwood, MA: Artech House, 2013 (ISBN 978-1-60807-170-8)
  http://www.artechhouse.com/Main/Books/Advances-in-FDTD-Computational-Electrodynamics-Pho-2011.aspx</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2013-01-22</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.5366</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
