<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T19:10:18Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1409.1191" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.1191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2014-09-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Ab initio properties of the ground-state polar and paramagnetic
  europium-alkali-metal-atom and europium-alkaline-earth-metal-atom molecules</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Tomza, Micha&#x142;</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Atomic Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Chemical Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  The properties of the electronic ground state of the polar and paramagnetic
europium-$S$-state-atom molecules have been investigated. Ab initio techniques
have been applied to compute the potential energy curves for the
europium-alkali-metal-atom, Eu$X$ ($X$=Li, Na, K, Rb, Cs),
europium-alkaline-earth-metal-atom, Eu$Y$ ($Y$=Be, Mg, Ca, Sr, Ba), and
europium-ytterbium, EuYb, molecules in the Born-Oppenheimer approximation for
the high-spin electronic ground state. The spin restricted open-shell coupled
cluster method restricted to single, double, and noniterative triple
excitations, RCCSD(T), was employed and the scalar relativistic effects within
the small-core energy-consistent pseudopotentials were included. The permanent
electric dipole moments and static electric dipole polarizabilities were
computed. The leading long-range coefficients describing the dispersion
interaction between atoms at large internuclear distances $C_6$ are also
reported. The EuK, EuRb, and EuCs molecules are examples of species possessing
both large electric and magnetic dipole moments making them potentially
interesting candidates for ultracold many-body quantum simulations when
confined in an optical lattice in combined electric and magnetic fields.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 8 pages, 5 figures, 1 table. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1306.5450</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2014-09-03</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1409.1191</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Phys. Rev. A 90, 022514 (2014)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevA.90.022514</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
