<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-08T10:33:53Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1409.1248" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.1248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-08-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Quantum Key Distribution using Continuous-variable non-Gaussian States</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Borelli, L. F. M.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Aguiar, L. S.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Roversi, J. A.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Vidiella-Barranco, A.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  In this work we present a quantum key distribution protocol using
continuous-variable non-Gaussian states, homodyne detection and post-selection.
The employed signal states are the Photon Added then Subtracted Coherent States
(PASCS) in which one photon is added and subsequently one photon is subtracted.
We analyze the performance of our protocol, compared to a coherent state based
protocol, for two different attacks that could be carried out by the
eavesdropper (Eve). We calculate the secret key rate transmission in a lossy
line for a superior channel (beam-splitter) attack, and we show that we may
increase the secret key generation rate by using the non-Gaussian PASCS rather
than coherent states. We also consider the simultaneous quadrature measurement
(intercept-resend) attack and we show that the efficiency of Eve's attack is
substantially reduced if PASCS are used as signal states.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: We have included an analysis of the simultaneous quadrature
  measurement attack plus 2 figures; we have also clarified some points</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2014-09-03</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2015-08-21</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1409.1248</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
