<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2016-02-09T17:51:07Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1505.00986" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-05-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Breaking the challenge of signal integrity using time-domain spoof
  surface plasmon polaritons</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Zhang, Hao Chi</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Cui, Tie Jun</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Zhang, Qian</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Fan, Yifeng</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Fu, Xiaojian</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  In modern integrated circuits and wireless communication systems/devices,
three key features need to be solved simultaneously to reach higher performance
and more compact size: signal integrity, interference suppression, and
miniaturization. However, the above-mentioned requests are almost contradictory
using the traditional techniques. To overcome this challenge, here we propose
time-domain spoof surface plasmon polaritons (SPPs) as the carrier of signals.
By designing a special plasmonic waveguide constructed by printing two narrow
corrugated metallic strips on the top and bottom surfaces of a dielectric
substrate with mirror symmetry, we show that spoof SPPs are supported from very
low frequency to the cutoff frequency with strong subwavelength effects, which
can be converted to the time-domain SPPs. When two such plasmonic waveguides
are tightly packed with deep-subwavelength separation, which commonly happens
in the integrated circuits and wireless communications due to limited space, we
demonstrate theoretically and experimentally that SPP signals on such two
plasmonic waveguides have better propagation performance and much less mutual
coupling than the conventional signals on two traditional microstrip lines with
the same size and separation. Hence the proposed method can achieve significant
interference suppression in very compact space, providing a potential solution
to break the challenge of signal integrity.
</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1505.00986</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
