<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-08T16:30:49Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1505.00912" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2015-11-11</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:cond-mat</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Thermodynamic Equilibrium as a Symmetry of the Schwinger-Keldysh Action</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Sieberer, L. M.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Chiocchetta, A.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Gambassi, A.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>T&#xe4;uber, U. C.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Diehl, S.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Condensed Matter - Statistical Mechanics</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  The time evolution of an extended quantum system can be theoretically
described in terms of the Schwinger-Keldysh functional integral formalism,
whose action conveniently encodes the information about the dynamics. We show
here that the action of quantum systems evolving in thermal equilibrium is
invariant under a symmetry transformation which distinguishes them from generic
open systems. A unitary or dissipative dynamics having this symmetry naturally
leads to the emergence of a Gibbs thermal stationary state. Moreover, the
fluctuation-dissipation relations characterizing the linear response of an
equilibrium system to external perturbations can be derived as the
Ward-Takahashi identities associated with this symmetry. Accordingly, the
latter provides an efficient check for the onset of thermodynamic equilibrium
and it makes testing the validity of fluctuation-dissipation relations
unnecessary. In the classical limit, this symmetry renders the one which is
known to characterize equilibrium in the stochastic dynamics of classical
systems coupled to thermal baths, described by Langevin equations.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 24 pages, 1 figure; final published version</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2015-11-10</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1505.00912</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Phys. Rev. B 92 (2015) 134307</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevB.92.134307</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
