<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-02-28T21:12:05Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1604.08901" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Entanglement sharing with separable states</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Mi&#x161;ta Jr, Ladislav</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We propose an entanglement sharing protocol based on separable states.
Initially, two parties, Alice and Bob, share a two-mode separable Gaussian
state. Alice then splits her mode into two separable modes and distributes them
between two players. Bob is separable from the players but he can create
entanglement with either of the players if the other player moves to his
location and collaborates with him. Any two parties are separable and the
creation of entanglement is thus mediated by transmission of a mode which is
separable from individual modes on Alice's and Bob's side. For the state shared
by the players and Bob one cannot establish entanglement between any two modes
even with the help of operation on the third mode provided that Bob is
restricted to Gaussian measurements and the state thus carries a nontrivial
signature of bound entanglement. The present protocol also demonstrates
switching between different separability classes of tripartite systems by
coherent operations on its bipartite parts and complements studies on protocols
utilizing mixed partially entangled multipartite states.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 8 pages, 3 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2016-04-29</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1604.08901</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Phys. Rev. A 87, 062326 (2013)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevA.87.062326</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
