<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-03-01T14:24:12Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1604.08809" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:cond-mat</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Dynamics of Hubbard Hamiltonians with the multiconfigurational
  time-dependent Hartree method for indistinguishable particles</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Lode, Axel U. J.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Bruder, Christoph</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Condensed Matter - Quantum Gases</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We apply the multiconfigurational time-dependent Hartree method for
indistinguishable particles (MCTDH-X) to systems of bosons or fermions in
lattices described by Hubbard type Hamiltonians with long-range or short-range
interparticle interactions. The wavefunction is expanded in a variationally
optimized time-dependent many-body basis generated by a set of effective
creation operators that are related to the original particle creation operators
by a time-dependent unitary transform. We use the time-dependent variational
principle for the coefficients of this transform as well as the expansion
coefficients of the wavefunction in the time-dependent many-body basis as
variational parameters to derive equations of motion. The convergence of
MCTDH-X is shown by comparing its results to the exact diagonalization of one-,
two-, and three-dimensional lattices filled with bosons with contact
interactions. We use MCTDH-X to study the buildup of correlations in the
long-time splitting dynamics of a Bose-Einstein condensate loaded into a large
two-dimensional lattice subject to a barrier that is ramped up in the center.
We find that the system is split into two parts with emergent time-dependent
correlations that depend on the ramping time -- for most barrier-raising-times
the system becomes two-fold fragmented, but for some of the very fast ramps,
the system shows revivals of coherence.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 18 pages, 4 figures. Software available at http:\\ultracold.org</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2016-04-29</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1604.08809</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Phys. Rev. A 94, 013616 (2016)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1103/PhysRevA.94.013616</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
