<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-02-28T15:18:03Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1712.00347" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.00347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>How can we erase states inside the black hole?</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Hwang, Junha</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Park, Hyosub</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Yeom, Dong-han</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Zoe, Heeseung</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>High Energy Physics - Theory</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>General Relativity and Quantum Cosmology</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We investigate an entangled system, which is analogous to a composite system
of a black hole and Hawking radiation. If Hawking radiation is well
approximated by an outgoing particle generated from a pair creation around the
black hole, such a pair creation increases the total number of states. There
should be a unitary mechanism to reduce the number of states inside the horizon
for black hole evaporation. Since the infalling antiparticle has negative
energy, as long as the infalling antiparticle finds its partner such that two
particles form a separable state, one can trace out such a zero energy system
by maintaining unitarity. In this paper, based on some toy model calculations,
we show that such a unitary tracing-out process is only possible before the
Page time, while it is impossible after the Page time. Hence, after the Page
time, if we assume that the process is unitary and the Hawking pair forms a
separable state, the internal number of states will monotonically increase,
which is supported by the AMPS argument. In addition, the Hawking particles
cannot generate randomness of the entire system and hence the entanglement
entropy cannot reach its maximum. Based on these results, we modify the correct
form of the Page curve for the remnant picture. The most important conclusion
is this: if we assume unitarity, semi-classical quantum field theory, and
general relativity, then the black hole should violate the Bekenstein-Hawking
entropy bound around the Page time at the latest, and hence, the infinite
production arguments for remnants might be applied for semi-classical black
holes, which seems very problematic.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 19 pages, 7 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1712.00347</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
