<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-03-01T16:00:01Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1712.00439" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.00439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:cond-mat</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Capsize of polarization in dilute photonic crystals</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Gevorkian, Zhyrair</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Hakhoumian, Arsen</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Gasparian, Vladimir</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Cuevas, Emilio</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Applied Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Condensed Matter - Other Condensed Matter</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Physics - Optics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We investigate, experimentally and theoretically, polarization rotation
effects in dilute photonic crystals with transverse permittivity inhomogeneity
perpendicular to the traveling direction of waves. A capsize, namely a drastic
change of polarization to the perpendicular direction is observed in a
one-dimensional photonic crystal in the frequency range $10\div 140$ GHz. To
gain more insights into the rotational mechanism, we have developed a
theoretical model of dilute photonic crystal, based on Maxwell's equations with
a spatially dependent two dimensional inhomogeneous dielectric permittivity. We
show that the polarization's rotation can be explained by an optical splitting
parameter appearing naturally in Maxwell's equations for magnetic or electric
fields components. This parameter is an optical analogous of Rashba like
spin-orbit interaction parameter present in quantum waves, introduces a
correction to the band structure of the two-dimensional Bloch states, creates
the dynamical phase shift between the waves propagating in the orthogonal
directions and finally leads to capsizing of the initial polarization.
Excellent agreement between theory and experiment is found.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 11pages,6figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2017-11-30</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1712.00439</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Scientific Reports, 7,16593,(2017)</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41598-017-16847-8</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
