<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2018-02-28T15:07:01Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:1712.00294" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1712.00294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-12-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>High-threshold fault-tolerant quantum computation with analog quantum
  error correction</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Fukui, Kosuke</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Tomita, Akihisa</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Okamoto, Atsushi</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Fujii, Keisuke</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  To implement fault-tolerant quantum computation with continuous variables,
the Gottesman-Kitaev-Preskill (GKP) qubit has been recognized as an important
technological element. However,it is still challenging to experimentally
generate the GKP qubit with the required squeezing level, 14.8 dB, of the
existing fault-tolerant quantum computation. To reduce this requirement, we
propose a high-threshold fault-tolerant quantum computation with GKP qubits
using topologically protected measurement-based quantum computation with the
surface code. By harnessing analog information contained in the GKP qubits, we
apply analog quantum error correction to the surface code.Furthermore, we
develop a method to prevent the squeezing level from decreasing during the
construction of the large scale cluster states for the topologically protected
measurement based quantum computation. We numerically show that the required
squeezing level can be relaxed to less than 10 dB, which is within the reach of
the current experimental technology. Hence, this work can considerably
alleviate this experimental requirement and take a step closer to the
realization of large scale quantum computation.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 13 pages, 7 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2017-12-07</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/1712.00294</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
