<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T18:52:42Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0310157" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0310157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Low Energy Quantum System Simulation</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Cho, Peter</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Berggren, Karl</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  A numerical method for solving Schrodinger's equation based upon a
Baker-Campbell-Hausdorff (BCH) expansion of the time evolution operator is
presented herein. The technique manifestly preserves wavefunction norm, and it
can be applied to problems in any number of spatial dimensions. We also
identify a particular dimensionless ratio of potential to kinetic energies as a
key coupling constant. This coupling establishes characteristic length and time
scales for a large class of low energy quantum states, and it guides the choice
of step sizes in numerical work. Using the BCH method in conjunction with an
imaginary time rotation, we compute low energy eigenstates for several quantum
systems coupled to non-trivial background potentials. The approach is
subsequently applied to the study of 1D propagating wave packets and 2D bound
state time development. Failures of classical expectations uncovered by
simulations of these simple systems help develop quantum intuition.
  Finally, we investigate the response of a Superconducting Quantum
Interference Device (SQUID) to a time dependent potential. We discuss how to
engineer the potential's energy and time scales so that the SQUID acts as a
quantum NOT gate. The notional simulation we present for this gate provides
useful insight into the design of one candidate building block for a quantum
computer.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 32 pages, 13 figures</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2003-10-26</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0310157</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
