<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T19:03:42Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0409215" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0409215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2009-11-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Ghost imaging schemes: fast and broadband</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Bache, M.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Brambilla, E.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Gatti, A.</dc:creator>
 <dc:creator>Lugiato, L. A.</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  In ghost imaging schemes information about an object is extracted by
measuring the correlation between a beam that passed the object and a reference
beam. We present a spatial averaging technique that substantially improves the
imaging bandwidth of such schemes, which implies that information about
high-frequency Fourier components can be observed in the reconstructed
diffraction pattern. In the many-photon regime the averaging can be done in
parallel and we show that this leads to a much faster convergence of the
correlations. We also consider the reconstruction of the object image, and
discuss the differences between a pixel-like detector and a bucket detector in
the object arm. Finally, it is shown how to non-locally make spatial filtering
of a reconstructed image. The results are presented using entangled beams
created by parametric down-conversion, but they are general and can be extended
also to the important case of using classically correlated thermal-like beams.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 15 pages, published in Optics Express. Figures in online version miss
  some information in axes labels, therefore we have updated the arXiv version
  to the published version and with the correct axes labels. The movies are
  available at the Optics Express home page</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2004-09-30</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2004-12-07</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0409215</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>Opt. Express 12, 6067-6081 (2004),
  http://www.opticsexpress.org/abstract.cfm?URI=OPEX-12-24-6067</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>doi:10.1364/OPEX.12.006067</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
