<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T19:17:48Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0105020" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0105020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>On Bell's Paradox</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Jongejan, Bart</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  The correlations between the outcomes of pairs of spin component measurements
on particles in the singlet state exist and can be observed independently of
any a priori given frame of reference. We can even construct a frame of
reference that is based on these correlations. This observation-based frame of
reference is equivalent to the customary a priori given frame of reference of
the laboratory when describing real Bohm-Aharonov experiments.
 J.S. Bell has argued that local hidden parameter theories that reproduce the
predictions of Quantum Mechanics cannot exist, but the counterfactual reasoning
leading to Bell's conclusion is physically meaningless if the frame of
reference that is based on spin component measurements is accepted as the
backdrop for Bohm-Aharonov experiments.
 The refutal of Bell's proof opens up for the construction of a viable hidden
parameter theory. A model of a spin h/2 particle in terms of a non-flat metric
of space-time is shown to allow the predictions of quantum mechanics in the
Bohm-Aharonov experiment to be reproduced, without introducing non-locality.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 13 pages, TeX, 2 figures (stereograms)</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2001-05-06</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0105020</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
