<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2015-12-28T18:52:42Z</responseDate>
<request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0410012" metadataPrefix="oai_dc">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<GetRecord>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0410012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2007-05-23</datestamp>
 <setSpec>math</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:math-ph</setSpec>
 <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
 <dc:title>Pseudo-Hermitian Description of PT-Symmetric Systems Defined on a
  Complex Contour</dc:title>
 <dc:creator>Mostafazadeh, Ali</dc:creator>
 <dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>High Energy Physics - Theory</dc:subject>
 <dc:subject>Mathematical Physics</dc:subject>
 <dc:description>  We describe a method that allows for a practical application of the theory of
pseudo-Hermitian operators to PT-symmetric systems defined on a complex
contour. We apply this method to study the Hamiltonians $H=p^2+x^2(ix)^\nu$
with $\nu\in(-2,\infty)$ that are defined along the corresponding anti-Stokes
lines. In particular, we reveal the intrinsic non-Hermiticity of $H$ for the
cases that $\nu$ is an even integer, so that $H=p^2\pm x^{2+\nu}$, and give a
proof of the discreteness of the spectrum of $H$ for all $\nu\in(-2,\infty)$.
Furthermore, we study the consequences of defining a square-well Hamiltonian on
a wedge-shaped complex contour. This yields a PT-symmetric system with a finite
number of real eigenvalues. We present a comprehensive analysis of this system
within the framework of pseudo-Hermitian quantum mechanics. We also outline a
direct pseudo-Hermitian treatment of PT-symmetric systems defined on a complex
contour which clarifies the underlying mathematical structure of the
formulation of PT-symmetric quantum mechanics based on the charge-conjugation
operator. Our results provide a conclusive evidence that pseudo-Hermitian
quantum mechanics provides a complete description of general PT-symmetric
systems regardless of whether they are defined along the real line or a complex
contour.
</dc:description>
 <dc:description>Comment: 28 pages, 1 figure, revised version, to appear in J. Phys. A</dc:description>
 <dc:date>2004-10-01</dc:date>
 <dc:date>2005-02-18</dc:date>
 <dc:type>text</dc:type>
 <dc:identifier>http://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0410012</dc:identifier>
 <dc:identifier>J.Phys. A38 (2005) 3213-3234</dc:identifier>
 </oai_dc:dc>
</metadata>
</record>
</GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>
